Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Katrin，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
This one is especially for people who are interested in babies.
这节课程特别适合对宝宝感兴趣的人。
That's right.
没错。
Maybe you have a baby, you will have a baby, maybe you're pregnant and this is a great
也许你有宝宝，或者即将有宝宝，又或者你怀孕了，这节课程非常棒，
lesson for that because we are talking about a baby shower.
因为我们讨论的是宝宝派对。
Okay, so before we get started, let's take a look at vocabulary preview and learn what
好的，在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览，了解一下
exactly a baby shower is.
宝宝派对到底是什么。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so a baby shower.
好的，宝宝派对。
You would think that this is about bathing the baby, about giving the baby a bath.
你可能会以为这是关于给宝宝洗澡的。
No, not a real shower.
不，不是真正的淋浴。
A baby shower or a bridal shower, these are parties.
宝宝派对或新娘派对，这些都是派对。
Okay, they're parties.
没错，它们是派对。
And in this case, a baby shower is a party that you throw for a woman that is pregnant,
在这种情况下，宝宝派对是为怀孕的女性举办的派对，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So if my sister is going to have a baby, I throw her a baby shower.
所以如果我姐姐要生宝宝了，我会为她举办一个宝宝派对。
It's a party where all of her friends give her gifts.
这是一个派对，她所有的朋友都会送她礼物。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, it's a way to celebrate having a baby.
是的，这是一种庆祝生宝宝的方式。
Okay, so they give her gifts, you'll play games as well as to like maybe guess the name
好的，所以他们会送她礼物，还会玩游戏，比如猜宝宝的名字
of the baby or guess the sex of the baby.
或猜宝宝的性别。
Exactly.
没错。
Stuff like that.
诸如此类的事情。
Okay, so it's a very common thing.
好的，所以这是很常见的事情。
I think it's mostly for women.
我觉得这主要是为女性举办的。
I don't really know if men have baby showers as well.
我不太确定男性是否也有宝宝派对。
I don't think so.
我觉得没有。
I don't think so either.
我也觉得没有。
But it's a very popular tradition in the United States and many other parts of the world.
但这是美国以及世界许多地方非常流行的传统。
So we're going to talk about that.
所以我们要讨论这个。
Let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
让我们第一次听对话。
Thank you for organizing this great baby shower for me.
谢谢你为我组织这个很棒的宝宝派对。
I've always been to baby showers but never actually had one held for me.
我一直参加别人的宝宝派对，但从来没人为我举办过。
Let's get started.
我们开始吧。
Okay, let's start opening some presents.
好的，我们开始拆一些礼物吧。
Oh, look, what a great little bib for the baby.
哦，看，多好的宝宝围兜啊。
This will definitely come in handy.
这肯定会派上用场。
Oh, wow, you also got me a stroller.
哦，哇，你还给我买了婴儿车。
That's so great.
太棒了。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
This next one is from Betty.
下一个是Betty送的。
A high chair and a car seat.
一个高脚椅和一个汽车安全座椅。
Wow, Betty, thank you so much.
哇，Betty，非常感谢你。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
One more from Carla.
还有一个是Carla送的。
A playpen and crib.
一个游戏围栏和婴儿床。
Thanks, Carla.
谢谢，Carla。
This is just what I needed.
这正是我需要的。
Okay, that's all of them.
好的，就这些了。
No more gifts.
没有更多礼物了。
Now who wants to guess when the baby is due?
现在谁来猜猜宝宝什么时候出生？
I think my water just broke.
我想我的羊水破了。
Get me to a hospital.
快送我去医院。
All right, so very interesting.
好的，非常有趣。
All the gifts that they got and definitely very useful because this is a very common
他们收到的所有礼物都非常有用，因为这些都是给宝宝准备的
items that you get for babies, right?
常见物品，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
This stuff is really, really valuable because if you have a baby or if your brother or sister
这些东西真的非常宝贵，因为如果你有宝宝，或者你的兄弟或姐妹
has a baby, you'll notice that these are very common items.
有宝宝，你会发现这些都是很常见的物品。
So let's go through a couple of them in today's Language Takeaway.
所以让我们在今天的语言要点中看看其中几个。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so the first word that we're going to take a look at, the most common one and useful
好的，我们要看的第一个词，最常见也最有用
one for a baby is a bib.
的宝宝用品是围兜。
Bib.
围兜。
So, babies are messy.
所以，宝宝们很邋遢。
When they eat food, they get their food on their clothes.
他们吃东西时，会把食物弄到衣服上。
So to protect the clothes, babies wear bibs.
所以为了保护衣服，宝宝们会戴围兜。
This is a piece of cloth or fabric around their neck.
这是一块围在他们脖子上的布或织物。
Okay, a bib.
好的，围兜。
And also, sometimes you want to go out with your baby to the mall, you're walking and
还有，有时候你想带宝宝去商场，你走着走着，
you don't want to carry him in your arms all the time.
不想一直抱着他。
So you need a stroller.
所以你需要一辆婴儿车。
Okay, so basically a stroller is a chair on wheels for a baby.
好的，所以婴儿车基本上就是带轮子的宝宝椅子。
Babies are heavy and as they get older, they get heavier.
宝宝很重，而且随着他们长大，会越来越重。
And so this is a way to push the baby around, not carry the baby.
所以这是一种推着宝宝走的方式，而不是抱着宝宝。
Right, and maybe the baby falls asleep, so they can fall asleep in the stroller.
对，而且宝宝可能会睡着，所以他们可以在婴儿车里睡觉。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, and while talking about chairs, we're going to take a look at two different types
好的，说到椅子，我们来看看两种不同类型的椅子。
of chairs.
椅子。
First one is a high chair.
第一种是高脚椅。
Okay, high chair.
好的，高脚椅。
Think about the word high, that means tall in this case.
想想“高”这个词，这里指的是高的意思。
A high chair is a chair for babies at the table.
高脚椅是给婴儿在餐桌旁用的椅子。
So if you put a baby on a regular chair, they can't eat with adults.
所以如果你把婴儿放在普通椅子上，他们没法跟大人一起吃饭。
Right, they're too small.
对，他们太小了。
So we give them high chairs so that they can sit a little bit higher and they can be at
所以我们给他们高脚椅，这样他们可以坐得高一点，就能跟大人一起在餐桌旁。
the table with adults.
跟大人一起在餐桌旁。
Exactly.
没错。
So they're very common.
所以它们很常见。
For example, you go to a restaurant, they will have a little high chairs if you have
比如，你去餐厅，如果你有婴儿或小孩，他们会有小高脚椅。
a baby or a small child.
有婴儿或小孩。
So if you're at a restaurant, you have a baby, you ask for a high chair.
所以如果你在餐厅，带着婴儿，你可以要一把高脚椅。
You say, do you have a high chair, please?
你会说，请问你们有高脚椅吗？
Yeah, perfect.
对，完美。
And well, if you're going to the restaurant or you go anywhere in your car, you need to
嗯，如果你要去餐厅或者开车去任何地方，你需要确保婴儿安全，显然他们没法坐在普通座位上。
have the baby be safe and obviously they can't fit on a normal seat.
没法坐在普通座位上。
No, with a seat belt?
用安全带也不行吗？
No, I don't think so.
不，我觉得不行。
So that's why you get them a car seat.
所以这就是为什么你要给他们买汽车安全座椅。
Okay, a car seat is a special chair that goes on the seat of the car and usually it's very,
好的，汽车安全座椅是一种特殊的椅子，放在汽车座位上，通常非常非常安全。
very safe.
非常安全。
It's made to protect the baby.
它是为了保护婴儿而设计的。
Right.
对。
So if you are ever in a car accident, the car seat will help protect the small baby.
所以如果你遇到车祸，汽车安全座椅能帮助保护小婴儿。
Right.
对。
So it's supposed to go in the back of the car, not the front.
所以它应该放在汽车后座，而不是前座。
Yes, always.
是的，总是这样。
Very good.
非常好。
And now moving on to our last two words.
现在来看最后两个词。
If you're at home, you sometimes want to have the baby play and you get them a play pen.
如果你在家，有时想让婴儿玩耍，你会给他们一个游戏围栏。
So basically this is a way for parents to leave the baby playing but not look at the
所以这基本上是一种让父母可以放婴儿在里面玩，但不用一直盯着看的方式。
baby the whole time.
不用一直盯着看。
Right.
对。
A play pen is like a cage for a baby, but it's soft and it's cute and it's pretty.
游戏围栏就像一个婴儿的笼子，但它是软的，可爱的，漂亮的。
So it's basically like an open area that's protected on the sides and the baby can go
所以它基本上是一个开放的区域，四周有保护，婴儿可以进去，但出不来。
inside but the baby can't leave.
但婴儿出不来。
Right.
对。
It's like a cage basically and it has little toys and that's the way you just keep them
它基本上像个笼子，里面有小玩具，这样你就可以让他们在里面待一会儿。
in there for a while.
让他们在里面待一会儿。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And now when you want to put the baby to sleep, it can't obviously sleep in a big bed because
现在，当你想让婴儿睡觉时，显然他们不能睡在大床上，因为可能会滚来滚去，可能会掉下来。
it might roll over, it might fall off.
可能会掉下来。
There's a lot of things that can go wrong, so you get them a crib.
有很多可能出问题的地方，所以你会给他们买婴儿床。
Right.
对。
So a crib is a bed for babies.
所以婴儿床是给婴儿用的床。
This is usually high off the ground and it's usually quite small and the baby can't climb
它通常离地面较高，而且通常很小，婴儿爬不出来。
out of it.
爬不出来。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
嗯。
So it's a very safe bed so the baby can't fall out, can't climb out.
所以这是一张非常安全的床，婴儿不会掉出来，也爬不出来。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So very interesting, very useful things for you if you're having a baby, planning on getting
所以如果你有婴儿，或者打算买这些东西，这些都非常有趣、非常有用。
these things.
打算买这些东西。
So why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
所以我们为什么不回去再听一遍对话，然后我们会回来做流利度练习。
Thank you for organizing this great baby shower for me.
谢谢你为我组织这个很棒的宝宝派对。
I've always been to baby showers but never actually had one held for me.
我以前参加过宝宝派对，但从来没人为我办过。
Let's get started.
我们开始吧。
Okay.
好的。
Let's start opening some presents.
我们开始拆礼物吧。
Oh look, what a great little bib for the baby.
哦看，多好的小围兜啊，给婴儿的。
This will definitely come in handy.
这肯定很实用。
Oh wow, you also got me a stroller.
哦哇，你还给我买了婴儿推车。
That's so great.
太棒了。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
This next one is from Betty.
下一个是贝蒂送的。
A high chair and a car seat.
一个高脚椅和一个汽车安全座椅。
Wow, Betty, thank you so much.
哇，贝蒂，太感谢你了。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
One more from Carla.
还有一个是卡拉送的。
A playpen and crib.
一个游戏围栏和婴儿床。
Thanks, Carla.
谢谢，卡拉。
This is just what I needed.
这正是我需要的。
Okay, that's all of them.
好了，就这些了。
No more gifts.
没有更多礼物了。
Now who wants to guess when the baby is due?
现在谁来猜猜预产期是什么时候？
I think my water just broke.
我想我羊水破了。
Get me to a hospital.
快送我去医院。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at two key phrases.
现在让我们来看看两个关键短语。
Easy Builder.
Easy Builder。
Okay, so at the beginning of the dialogue, the woman receives a bib for the baby and
好的，在对话开头，那位女士收到了一件婴儿围兜，
she says, this will definitely come in handy.
她说，这个肯定派得上用场。
To come in handy.
派得上用场。
Right, so when something comes in handy, it means it will be useful.
对，所以当某物“派得上用场”时，意思是它会有用。
Okay, so something that's handy is useful.
好的，所以“handy”的东西就是有用的。
To come in handy means to be useful.
“派得上用场”意思是有用。
It will be useful in the future.
它将来会有用。
So for example, you should take a flashlight with you in the car just in case because it
比如，你应该在车里带个手电筒以防万一，因为它
could come in handy.
可能派得上用场。
That's right.
没错。
Or if I know that Marco is traveling to India, I can give him a map of India.
或者如果我知道马可要去印度旅行，我可以给他一张印度地图。
I say, Marco, this map might come in handy.
我说，马可，这张地图可能派得上用场。
Exactly.
正是。
Very good.
非常好。
So to come in handy or in something that is handy, something that's useful.
所以“派得上用场”或“handy”的东西，就是有用的东西。
And towards the end, a very popular phrase you probably heard in every movie that has
在结尾处，有一个非常流行的短语，你可能在每部有
like maybe a pregnant woman in there.
孕妇的电影里都听过。
My water just broke.
我羊水破了。
My water broke.
Okay, so the woman says, my water broke.
好的，所以那位女士说，我羊水破了。
Take me to the hospital.
送我去医院。
Right.
对。
Okay, so this means I'm having my baby right now.
好的，所以这意味着我现在要生孩子了。
So why do they say that the water broke?
那为什么他们说“羊水破了”？
Because actually water kind of breaks, right?
因为实际上水是破了的，对吧？
I think there's a protective water cushion.
我想有一个保护性的水囊。
Basically there's a sack of water protecting the baby.
基本上有一个水袋保护着婴儿。
It's not just water.
那不只是水。
It's all sorts of like body fluids.
那是各种体液。
And basically when that breaks, it comes out and you know that you're going to have the
基本上当那个破了，液体流出来，你就知道要生
baby because that means the baby has to come out now because that protective fluid is gone.
孩子了，因为这意味着婴儿必须出来了，因为保护液没了。
Maybe the baby just kind of kicks that water out and just like, I'm ready to come out.
也许婴儿只是踢破了那个水囊，然后就像，我准备好出来了。
I have no idea how it works.
我不知道具体怎么回事。
All right, so very interesting stuff.
好了，非常有趣的内容。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Thank you for organizing this great baby shower for me.
谢谢你为我组织这个这么棒的宝宝派对。
I've always been to baby showers but never actually had one held for me.
我参加过很多宝宝派对，但从来没人为我办过。
Let's get started.
我们开始吧。
Okay, let's start opening some presents.
好的，我们开始拆礼物吧。
Oh look, what a great little bib for the baby.
哦看，多好的小围兜啊。
This will definitely come in handy.
这个肯定派得上用场。
Oh wow, you also got me a stroller.
哦哇，你还给我买了婴儿车。
That's so great.
太好了。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
This next one is from Betty.
下一个是贝蒂送的。
A high chair and a car seat.
一个高脚椅和一个汽车安全座椅。
Wow, Betty, thank you so much.
哇，贝蒂，太感谢你了。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
One more from Carla.
还有一个是卡拉送的。
A playpen and crib.
一个游戏围栏和婴儿床。
Thanks Carla.
谢谢卡拉。
That's just what I needed.
这正是我需要的。
Okay, that's all of them.
好了，就这些了。
No more gifts.
没有更多礼物了。
Now who wants to guess when the baby is due?
现在谁来猜猜预产期是什么时候？
I think my water just broke.
我想我羊水破了。
Get me to a hospital.
快送我去医院。
All right, so talking about baby things and baby showers.
好了，聊了宝宝用品和宝宝派对。
It's a very interesting tradition.
这是一个非常有趣的习俗。
I understand that in other countries they don't really celebrate baby showers like this.
我知道在其他国家，他们并不像这样庆祝宝宝派对。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, or that if they do, they do it in different ways.
是的，或者即使庆祝，方式也不同。
I know for example that sometimes in Latin American countries, they usually do it after
我知道比如在拉丁美洲国家，他们通常在
the baby's born.
宝宝出生后办。
Oh, so like a congratulations shower.
哦，所以像是一个祝贺派对。
Exactly.
正是。
And then obviously you know if the baby was a boy or a girl, so then you get them like
然后显然你知道宝宝是男孩还是女孩，所以你可以给他们
pink things or blue things.
粉色的或蓝色的东西。
So it's a little bit more.
所以更具体一些。
That's what's really funny about these.
这就是这些派对有趣的地方。
People often want to have the surprise of not knowing if the baby will be a boy or a
人们常常想保留惊喜，不知道宝宝是男孩还是
girl.
女孩。
So when they have the baby shower, they say, oh, I don't know what the gender is.
所以当他们办宝宝派对时，他们说，哦，我不知道性别。
And so you end up buying all of these yellow things because yellow is neutral.
结果你买了所有这些黄色的东西，因为黄色是中性的。
It's good for boys and girls.
对男孩和女孩都合适。
I don't know how many yellow gifts I've got.
我不知道收到了多少黄色的礼物。
I think it's a very interesting thing because for example, I know that in China, I think
我觉得这挺有意思的，因为比如说，我知道在中国，我认为
you can't ask the doctor for the gender of the baby before it's born, right?
你不能在宝宝出生前问医生性别，对吧？
I think that's a way to, I'm not sure if it's a rule or not, but it sounds right.
我觉得这是一种方式，我不确定是不是规定，但听起来挺对的。
I mean, it's a way to protect female babies.
我的意思是，这是保护女婴的一种方式。
I think it would be always great to just have it be a surprise.
我觉得一直保持惊喜总是很好的。
You never know.
你永远不知道。
Yeah, just like, oh, you know, whatever comes out.
是啊，就像，哦，你知道，不管出来什么。
Can you imagine not knowing and then you have twins?
你能想象不知道结果却生了双胞胎吗？
That would be great for me, I think, if I had like a boy and a girl, bam, all at once.
对我来说那太棒了，我想，如果我有了一男一女，砰，一次搞定。
All at once, never have to worry about it again.
一次搞定，再也不用担心了。
Exactly, and then you have the best of both worlds, right?
没错，然后你就两全其美了，对吧？
You're done.
你就完事了。
All right, so very interesting topic.
好了，这是个很有趣的话题。
Let us know if you have baby showers in your country or how do you celebrate a baby's birth
告诉我们你们国家有没有宝宝派对，或者你们怎么庆祝宝宝出生
or before it's born?
或者出生前？
What do you do?
你们做什么？
Very good question.
很好的问题。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right, bye.
好了，再见。
We'll talk to you then.
我们到时候聊。